A Guide to the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Weather Bureau (Richmond, Va.), Records 1897-1979
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
U.S. Department of Agriculture, Weather Bureau (Richmond, Va.), Records, 1897-1979
The Library of Virginia
44233
33 cu. ft. (106 volumes housed in 23 boxes and 54 volumes on shelf)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor information unavailable.
Biographical Information
The U.S. Weather Bureau was established by an act of Congress on 1 October 1890. It took over the weather service that had been established in the Office of the Chief Signal Officer of the War Department in 1870. The duties of the Weather Bureau included forecasting, recording climatological data, and making meteorological observations and reports. The Bureau was transferred to the Department of Commerce in 1940.
Scope and Content
Records, 1897-1979, relating to weather observation by the United States Weather Bureau's Richmond station, located in Richmond, Virginia. Included are volumes containing Monthly Records of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summaries containing weather observations such as maximum and minimum temperatures; precipitation levels, character of the day (cloudy or clear); barometer pressure; dew-point; thermograph and barograph readings; hours of sunshine; wind velocity; and miscellaneous phenomena such as frosts, thunderstorms, solar halos, and lunar halos. In 1905 the volumes included a map of the United States and contain notations on the temperatures and weather systems across the country. Later the volumes include Local Climatological Data and Surface Weather Observations, with the same type of information. Reports were taken from the airport office at Byrd Field (WBAS) and the city office at Chimboraza Park (WBO).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Original Monthly Record of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summary, 1897-1898. (Box 1)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summary, 1899. (Box 1)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summary, 1900. (Box 1)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summary, 1901. (Box 2)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summary, 1902. (Box 2)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summary, 1903. (Box 2)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations and Annual Meteorological Summary, 1904. (Box 3)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1905. (Box 3)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1906. (Box on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1907. (Box 4)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1908. (Box 4)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1909.
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1910. (Box on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1911. (Box on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1912. (Box on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1913. (Box 6)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1914. (Box 6)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1915. (Box 7)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1916. (Box 7)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1917. (Box 8)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1918. (Box 8)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1919. (Box 9)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1920. (Box 9)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1921. (Box 10)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1922. (Box 10)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1923. (Box 11)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1924. (Box 11)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1925. (Box 12)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1926. (Box 12)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1927. (Box 13)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1928. (Box 13)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1929. (Box 14)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1930. (Box 14)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1931. (Box 15)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1932. (Box on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1933. (Box 16)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1934. (Box 16)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1935. (Box 17)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1936. (Box 17)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1937. (Box 18)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1938. (Box 18)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1939. (Box 19)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1940. (Box 19)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1941. (Box 20)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1942. (Box 20)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1943. (Box 21)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1944. (Box 21)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1945. (Box 22)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1946. (Box 22)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1947. (Box on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1947 January-1948 December. (Box 23)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1948. (Box 23)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1949. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1949-1950. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1950. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1951. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1951-1952. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1952. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1953. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1953. (Volume on shelf (M) (VOL. 53))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1954. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1955. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1956. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1957. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1958. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1959. (Volume on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1960 January-June. (Volume on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1960 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1961 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1961 July-December. (Volume on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1962 January-June. (Volume on shelf (M))
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1962 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1963 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1963 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1964 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1964 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1965 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1965 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1966 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1966 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1967 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1967 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1968 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1968 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1969 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1969 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1970 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1970 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1971 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1971 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1972 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1972 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1973 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1973 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1974 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1974 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1975 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1975 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1976 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1976 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1977 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1977 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1978 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1978 July-December. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1979 January-June. (Volume on shelf)
- Original Monthly Record of Observations, 1979 July-December. (Volume on shelf)